Mohammed Rishad V K

Senior Software Engineer (Python, Django, FastAPI, Postgres, RestAPI, AWS, Docker, Golang)

More than 7 years of experience working with Scalable, Reusable, Reliable, Object Oriented Programming(OOP), Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) in Software Development. I'm a quick learner and highly flexible to adapt to new challenges, take ownership, handle multiple responsibilities and mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

Backend Tools Engineer, Chronext Service Germany GmbH

KÖLN. GERMANY

Aug 2023 - Present

- Development of internal tools for supply, workshop, logistics, etc and connect with other microservices.
- Implemented automation solutions to streamline internal workflows and processes, resulting in a significant productivity increase of 5x.
- Applied data engineering techniques using MySQL, Redshift, Airflow, Tableau, and other relevant technologies for reporting.
- Taking responsibility for releases / deployments of services.
- Technologies
 - Python, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, RestAPI, Redis, MySQL, SQLAlchemy, Airflow, Docker, BI, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, SQS, SES, , EC2, EKS, RedShift, React, API Gatewayt, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Data warehouse, Tableau

Backend Developer, StudySmarter GmbH

MUNICH, GERMANY (REMOTE FROM INDIA)

Dec 2021 - May 2023

- Taking ownership for the development and maintaining different learning modes like Practice, Quiz, Spaced Repetition, Type to answer, etc.
- Improvising and adding new feature to core product like Flashcards,
 Documents, Summary, Textbook, Exercises, etc.
- Collaborating with team and cross functional team to achieve common goals.
- Writing unittest, integration, functional, etc to make sure quality of the product.
- Peer code review with cross functional teams.
- Technologies
 - Python, Django, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, RestAPI, Redis, Celery,
 RabbitMQ, Docker, Elastic Search, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, CloudFront,
 Sentry, CloudWatch, EC2, EKS, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Senior Software Engineer, Reckonsys Tech Labs Pvt. Ltd

BENGALURU, KARNATAKA, INDIA

May 2019 - Nov 2021

- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the business to implement features and understand use cases (US, Europe, India).

Gottesweg 83, Köln 50969, Germany

+49 15510 113900 mohammedrishad.vk@gmail.com

LINKS

- Website
- LinkedIn
- Github
- StackOverflow

SKILLS

Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, GraphQL, RestAPI, CSS., PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, HTML, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Git, AWS, GCP, API Gateway, PyTest, Airflow, SQLAlchemy, Unittest, Linux(Ubuntu), Unix, Jira, Agile

Familiar:

Kubernetes, Elixir, Phoenix, Node.js, Express JS, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, XML, JSON, Elastic Search, Numpy, Pandas, Mac OS, Windows, Terraform, Kafka, Data Structures, Algorithms

AWARDS & HONORS

SayOne Rockstar – Best Performer (Dec 2018).

Winner Djangothon2018 by HackerEarth (1st Prize Winner).

Acknowledged by Google, Microsoft, Sony, Freelancer, Kaspersky, eBay, CRIS, etc. for reporting security bugs.

LANGUAGES

- English (Proficient, C1)
- German (Beginner, A1)
- Malayalam (Native, C2)

- Contribute to design and development of Backend and API's using Monolith and Microservice Architecture.
- Contribute to the technical design and development APIs with performance and scalability in mind.
- Research, suggest and implement new solutions in performance of backend service
- Integration of third-party API's and creating webhooks for the business.
- Experience with devops and infrastructure practices and technology like CI, deployment automation, provisioning, Amazon AWS.
- Mentoring and training new joinees and juniors.
- Some industries worked are Hotel, Sports, Hiring, Transport, Aviation, Healthcare, Analytics, Travel, etc.

Technologies

 Python, Go(Golang), Django, Flask, FastAPI, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, GraphQL, RestAPI, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Elixir / Phoenix, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Docker, Elastic Search, Git, AWS, S3, SNS, SES, CloudFront, IAM, Lambda, EC2, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

Clients

 NuFlights, ClipHire, Pharmallama, TransportSimple, Acumen Aviation, Kiplist, D8aDriven, Moonllight, Vigna World

Software Engineer, SayOne Technologies Pvt. Ltd

KOCHI, KERALA, INDIA

Feb 2018 - May 2019

- Help to develop 5+ web applications from scratch.
- Managed team of 4 members including Backend and Frontend Developers.
- Developed a highly scalable ecommerce SaaS platform for independent pet retailers with Django and Postgres. (Worked on DB Design, Dashboard(Role, Orders, Invoicing, Products, Theming, Coupon, Offers) and Frontend Pages, etc)
- Design and develop robust services in coordination with frontend developers and produce well-tested, high quality code.
- Work directly with the client to implement features and understand use cases.
- Developed and maintained an article website for big data, blockchain, and artificial intelligence having insights and jobs..

Technologies

Python / Django, Flask, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 TypeScript, Angular, Celery, Redis, Elastic Search, RestAPI, Git,
 SendGrid, Kafka

Clients

o <u>eTailPet</u>, <u>FeedMyFurBaby</u>, <u>Dataflog</u>, <u>Mavin</u>, <u>BeCo</u>, <u>ProteinForPets</u>,

EDUCATION

University of Calicut — M.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA

2014 - 2016

- Blue Card Eligible EU / German
- Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 7.13/10 (71.3 %) A grade

University of Calicut — B.Sc Computer Science

MALAPPURAM, KERALA

2011 - 2014

Cumulative Grade Point Average(CGPA): 2.76/4 (69 %) - B grade

INTERESTS

- Open Source Contribution
- Web Security Research
- Mentoring
- Continuous Learning
- Photography
- Travel
- Football (Soccer)